ONUR KORDOĞAN

FRONTEND DEVELOPER

E-mail: onurkordogan@gmail.com
Linkedin: Onur Kordoğan
Address: Hatay / Turkey

GitHub : https://github.com/OnurKor

SUMMARY

+2 years experienced in IT and a **diligent** front-end developer. Have one of the most vital skills in the 21st century which is the **self-learning**. Eager to widen **algorithmic** horizons by exploring new programming techniques. Always tend to **collaborate**, enjoy verbal communications with colleagues, and highly value **experience** sharing. Able to grasp both new IT trends and upcoming innovations. Not only develop projects that are assigned to me but also desire to contribute the **efficiency** of projects since holding the Bachelor Degree at the **Industrial Engineering**. Looking forward to enhancing my knowledge of **backend** frameworks along with **frontend** technologies focused on User Interface applications by gaining qualified experiences. Especially interested in the **Front end/Web Development**, **HTML**, **CSS**, **JS**, **React**. Excited to learn new things and improve, lifetime student.

PROJECTS

HTML-CSS

- Parallax Web Site: Our goal in this project was to improve the use of the parallax effect on the site, Skills/Tools: HTML CSS Frameworks
- **Google Landing Page**: Our aim in this project is to repeat the CSS and HTML skills by creating the google homepage digital twin. Skills/Toolls: HTML CSS Frameworks.

Javascript

- **Ios Calculator**: In this project, the goal is to make a functional and visual clone of the calculator of an iOS device. *Skills/Tools*: *HTML*, *CSS Frameworks*, *JS Dom Manipulation and Event Listeners*.
- **To Do App**: In this project, a simple To-Do application was made using the array structure. User can add task from bowser, mark tasks as completed and delete them. Completed/total number of tasks can be displayed with a counter. Skills/Tools: JS Dom Manipulation and Event Listeners.
- Checkout Page: Our goal was to develop a real e-commerce website's checkout page for that project. There is a cart for buying products, and we can increase or decrease the number of products. By changing a parameter in the cart, our js functions calculate the cart total price. DOM, iterator, callback functions, string-array functions and events are used in our page. Additionally, we can remove products from the cart by clicking the remove button and decreasing the amount to "0". In that case, our page asks us to delete the product from the cart. As soon as you confirm the deletion, the sour chart total is recalculated by the js functions. Skills/Tools: DOM, Iterator, Callback functions, String-array functions and Events.
- **Find Number :** In this project, the goal is for a player to guess a randomly determined number. Skills/Tools: HTML, CSS Frameworks, *JS Dom Manipulation and Event Listeners*.

• Lottery Game: In this project, the aim is to determine the lotto numbers as many as 1 to 8 numbers received from the user. Skills/Tools: HTML, CSS Frameworks, *JS Dom Manipulation and Event Listeners*.

React Js

- Language Card: In this Project, IT language card is desinged using React.js useState and hooks, Skills/Tools: React, CSS
- Tour App: In this Project, tour guide is desinged using React useState and hooks, Skills/Tools: React.SCSS
- Recipe App: In this Project, recipe is designed using React useState and hooks, I got from data from API with fetch. Skills/Tools: React,CSS,Fetch
- Movie App: In this project, it is aimed to display cinema posters by using the tmdb api. There is a search feature according to the entered word. Skills/Tools: React-router library, Bootstrap library, Axios library and Firebase
- Task Tracker: In this Project, recipe is desinged using React useState and hooks, Skills/Tools: React.CSS

PROFESSIONAL SKILLS

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- ✓ HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript
- ✓ React.js, Redux
- ✓ SASS, SCSS, Bootstrap, Material.UI
- ✓ Python
- ✓ SQL
- ✓ Git, GitHub
- ✓ APIs & RESTful APIs
- ✓ Agile, Jira, SDLC
- ✓ Linux Basic, VS Code
- ✓ OOP

SOFT SKILLS

- ✓ Analytical Thinking, Creativity
- ✓ Time Management
- ✓ Idea Exchange
- ✓ Self-discipline
- ✓ Problem-solving Abilities
- ✓ Self-motivated, Strong Communication
- ✓ Ability Asking to Google
- ✓ Collaboration & Teamwork
- ✓ Coaching Mindset
- ✓ Resilience

WORK EXPERIENCE

IT Student Mentor, Clarusway LLC, US

July 2021 - PRESENT

- Developed interactive, responsive and scalable frontend using HTML5, CSS3, javascript ES6, React,
- Designing a website with HTML, CSS, SASS(SCSS) and Bootstrap-5 codes,
- Developing the payment page of the e-commerce website with JS functions using DOM, iterator, callback functions, string array functions and events,
- Requesting apis using Async, Await and Fetch structures to view data from various platforms,
- Enabling customers to make transactions on their websites using json, local storage, and array methods,

- Using state hook and component structures in various projects
- Working with React-router, bootstrap and axios libraries for user-friendly preparation of prepared websites,
- Combined Material UI and Semantic UI libraries to achieve better UI experience,
- State management applied using React States and Redux,
- Built a Dashboard page showing data related to users integrated with Database,
- Experienced in writing modular and reusable codes, using build tools and package managers,
- Studied on Computational Thinking, Operating Systems, Linux, Version Control Systems(Git & Github),
 Software Development Life Cycle (SDLC),
- Used SCRUM & Agile methodologies and JIRA while working on individual & group projects.

Officer (Lieutenant), Turkish Army, Turkey

2015 - 2021

- Planning Manoeuvres, Assigning Duties and Communicating effectively with other staff commanding, training and leading others
- Monitoring the Welfare and Progress of New Recruits
- Operating and Maintaining Warfare Systems, Equipment and Vehicles
- Taking on Specialist Duties and Skills such as Engineering, Training and Administration
- Producing Briefings, Reports and Presentations
- Distributing Equipment, Resources and Manpower.

CERTIFICATIONS

- Clarusway HTML & CSS Course Certificate
- Clarusway JavaScript Course Certificate
- Clarusway React Course Certificate
- Clarusway Frontend Course Certificate

EDUCATION

IT Fundamentals/ FullStack Developer

Clarusway IT Training School, March 2021 – July 2022

Dynamic learning experience on understanding & applying the Frontend, Backend Programming Languages, developing projects and accessing to the competence level to work with project management systems, different programming languages, frameworks and libraries including HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Python, React.Js, SQL, Django, Github, JIRA, Agile.

Industrial Engineering

Turkish National Defense University, 2011-2015

Bachelor's Degree,

Graduated with 3,57 GPA out of 4.00

LANGUAGE COMPETENCIES

Turkish: Native

English: Intermediate